<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <title><![CDATA[Christian Ternus]]></title>
  <link href="https://cternus.net//atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://cternus.net/"/>
  <updated>2017-08-14T14:17:06+00:00</updated>
  <id>https://cternus.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Christian Ternus]]></name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://gohugo.io/">Hugo</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[RC Day 0: Welcome, Meeting, Panels, and Presentations]]></title>
    <link href="https://cternus.net/blog/2017/08/14/rc-day-0--welcome--meeting--panels--and-presentations/"/>
    <updated>2017-08-14T14:17:06+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://cternus.net/blog/2017/08/14/rc-day-0--welcome--meeting--panels--and-presentations/</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='image'><a href='/uploads/2017/8/14/2017-08-14_15.57.02.jpg'><img src='/uploads/2017/8/14/2017-08-14_15.57.02-640x480.jpg' class='uploaded-img' /></a></div>

<p>First day of RC highlights included:</p>

<ul>
<li>Whirlwind meet-and-greet, where the most common question was &ldquo;so what are you working on?&rdquo; for current folks and &ldquo;what do you want to work on&rdquo; for new folks</li>
<li>A discussion of &ldquo;what are you excited about&rdquo; and &ldquo;what are you nervous about&rdquo;:</li>
</ul>

<div class='image'><a href='/uploads/2017/8/14/2017-08-14_18.35.42.jpg'><img src='/uploads/2017/8/14/2017-08-14_18.35.42-640x480.jpg' class='uploaded-img' /></a></div>

<ul>
<li><p>Panels about self-direction, choosing and scoping projects, and common struggles and how to cope with them. Oneof the stand-out aspects of RC is the strong focus on well-being, empathy, and kindness in addition to the programming/technical stuff. Definitely something that&rsquo;s missing in a lot of other technical spaces.</p></li>

<li><p>A skit about the RC <a href="https://www.recurse.com/manual#sec-environment">social rules</a> &ndash; much better than that sounds:</p></li>
</ul>

<div class='image'><a href='/uploads/2017/8/14/2017-08-14_17.29.48.jpg'><img src='/uploads/2017/8/14/2017-08-14_17.29.48-640x480.jpg' class='uploaded-img' /></a></div>

<ul>
<li>Presentations! I gave a presentation based on my <a href="https://blogs.akamai.com/2013/11/so-you-want-to-secure-something.html">So You Want To Secure Something</a> Akamai blog post. In retrospect, it was too much content to fit into five minutes, especially without slides. Hopefully I succeeded in conveying my key message: security doesn&rsquo;t have to be scary, it <em>is</em> something every Recurser can learn, and learning doesn&rsquo;t have to be a painful process.</li>
</ul>

<p>I spent the break time researching a better way to pair people up for the meet-and-greet, in the process learning about the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Assignment_problem">assignment problem</a> and the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stable_roommates_problem">stable roommate problem</a> &ndash; a variant of the stable marriage problem I learned about in discrete math.</p>

<p>Tomorrow is the first &ldquo;real day&rdquo; of RC. I think I&rsquo;m going to push myself to pair with folks &ndash; possibly putting up a sign saying what I&rsquo;d like help with. There are a lot of folks here experienced in frontend dev/data presentation as well as folks who&rsquo;ve been learning Rust, two areas I could definitely start out in.</p>

<p>Overall I&rsquo;m super happy and excited for what the next twelve weeks will bring. Onward!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[RC Day -1: Goals for RC]]></title>
    <link href="https://cternus.net/blog/2017/08/13/rc-day--1--rc-goals/"/>
    <updated>2017-08-13T22:48:04+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://cternus.net/blog/2017/08/13/rc-day--1--rc-goals/</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[

<p>Tomorrow begins my 12-week stint at the <a href="https://recurse.com">Recurse Center</a>, hereafter &ldquo;RC&rdquo; :)</p>

<p>In the spirit of SMART goals, here are some specific, measurable, achievable, relevant, and timely goals I&rsquo;ll grade myself on at the end of RC.</p>

<h3 id="pair-with-people-and-build-great-relationships">Pair with people and build great relationships</h3>

<p>RC&rsquo;s guide mentions that &ldquo;I wish I had paired more&rdquo; is one of the most frequent pieces of feedback from alumni &ndash; even when they&rsquo;ve been told this in advance!</p>

<p>Having social anxiety, this isn&rsquo;t the easiest thing in the world for me, but it&rsquo;s something I&rsquo;d like to get better at. RC will be full of fascinating people with skills I don&rsquo;t have, and sharpening my programming and interpersonal skills by learning from those folks &ndash; as well as imparting what knowledge I can &ndash; is the primary reason I applied in the first place!</p>

<p>So, note to self: when you&rsquo;re thinking that it&rsquo;s easier to just spend a few hours by yourself, remember this and try to fit in some pairing time.</p>

<p><em>How will I measure this</em>: in the 12 weeks I was at RC, did I pair at least 36 times (3x/week)? Have I made connections &ndash; new friends, colleagues, etc. &ndash; that I&rsquo;ll stick with after RC is over?</p>

<h3 id="build-something-cool-to-show-off">Build something cool to show off</h3>

<p>One possible idea I had for this is to try to resurrect My Favorite Weather Site of All Time, the late lamented WeatherSpark. The site was the best presentation of weather data I&rsquo;d ever seen, but it died an ignoble death thanks to being written entirely in Flash. Take a look &ndash; how awesome is this?</p>

<p><img src="/uploads/2017/8/13/weatherspark-screen-capture.jpg" alt="weatherspark-screen-capture.jpg" /></p>

<p><em>How will I measure this</em>: did I produce at least one complete project? Was I happy with it?</p>

<h3 id="renew-and-continue-building-my-programming-and-systems-skills">Renew and continue building my programming and systems skills</h3>

<p>The job I just left was educational in many ways, but it didn&rsquo;t leave much time for nose-to-the-grindstone programming. I&rsquo;d like to get back into systems development as well as work on some new skills. These might include:</p>

<ul>
<li>A new language: Rust, Clojure, Ruby</li>
<li>Refamiliarizing myself with a known language: Lisp, Scheme, C/C++, Javascript</li>
<li>A new problem domain: machine learning, graphics, native applications, compilers</li>
<li>Deep dives into security</li>
</ul>

<p><em>How will I measure this</em>: can I point to at least one concrete thing a week that I didn&rsquo;t know before?</p>

<h3 id="share-my-knowledge-with-others">Share my knowledge with others</h3>

<p>I&rsquo;ve acquired a reasonable amount of hard-won security knowledge in my time at Akamai, some of which is likely to be of interest to other folks. I&rsquo;ve also had a good amount of experience interviewing people &ndash; perhaps I can help others to interview?</p>

<p><em>How will I measure this</em>: are there people who can say I&rsquo;ve helped them?</p>

<h3 id="make-more-public-contributions">Make more public contributions</h3>

<p>These might include:</p>

<ul>
<li>blog posts</li>
<li>programming-related tweets</li>
<li>talks</li>
<li>conference applications</li>
</ul>

<p><em>How will I measure this</em>: did I make at least one significant public contribution per week?</p>

<h3 id="embrace-serendipity">Embrace serendipity</h3>

<p>RC will certainly involve challenges and new domains I&rsquo;d never expected.</p>

<p><em>How will I measure this</em>: did I take advantage of opportunities that came my way? Did I display adaptability in the face of new challenges?</p>

<h2 id="and-so-it-begins">And so it begins</h2>

<p>Come back in 12 weeks to see how I did :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
